[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Okay, this is getting real.
I'm being tracked.
So, my options are to either keep
the suit on or else strip down.
I don't mind walking around naked,
but I do mind bullets.
If I keep the suit on, I'll still
have people trying to kill me
...which, I'm kind of used to anyway...
But if I take it off and I get shot,
then, that's it.
I'm fucked.
You know what I'm saying, man?
You should!
You don't even have a weapon!
And don't think I'm
going to give you one.
Well, I'm not stripping in front of you,
in case you're wondering.
There's too many damned
people in this building.
Woah-ho...drafty.
Okay...
Oh, my god, it's cold in here!
IS THIS 10 FUCKING KELVIN?!
[shivering, muttering]
Don't get locked...
Don't get locked out in the open...
[shivering, muttering]
....okayokayokaywarmwarmwarm...
...okayokaywarmwarmpipes, warm pipes...
....warm pipes good.
Warm pipes...
Oh...ooh...
Frosty.
Well, I was wrong about one thing:
Those aliens are NOT from a swamp planet.
Anything that can--
Oh, my god.
This whole neighborhood's going to hell.
What, with the gangs...
[vortigaunt attack]
Yep...
Can't even walk down the street
of your own planet anymore!
I remember the good old days, when
I didn't have to bring a gun to work,
my coworkers weren't space bugs,
I had a salary,
I wasn't wanted by the government,
then YOU happened!
Ow!
Was I shot in the back of the--
[vortigese]
No respect, man.  No respect at all.
God damned outworlders
are ruining this country.
There was a time when
we'd put you all in cages.
And, if it was up to me,
it'd still be that way.
Some of you keep
zapping me with electricity.
That means you're a power source.
We should be taking advantage of that.
This is all so wasted.
Guard: Freeman, right?
Yeah?
Guard: I got a message for you.
Guard: Make sure you don't--
[gunshot]
Guard: Augh...
Daah!
Okay!  10-4!
I'll be sure not to do that!
Eh, my intuition tells me
that wasn't the full message.
Something about him killing himself
to make a point doesn't add up.
That, and the silenced gunshot
makes me think
there's something devious going on here.
Ah-hah!
Hm.
I don't see anyone.
Maybe the problem went away.
Maybe I willed it out of existence.
Maybe it was the magical
sniper fairy that comes and gives
silenced hollow-point rounds to
people who don't eat their vegetables.
That was one of the Grimm's Tales, right?
[gunshots]
Ah, ah, ah!
Ninjas!
These aren't fairies!  They're ninjas!
[gunshots]
Okay, move, move, move!
In order to beat a ninja,
I have to think like a ninja!
[gunshots]
Flank, flank, flank!
Double back!
[gunshots]
I trace electron orbits!
You think I can't find you?
[gunshots]
Fucking ninjas, man.
Oh ho!  Ninja in the closet.
Ninja in the closet!
Oh, some ammo.
Yeah, I think I'll take that.
Ninjas, man.
I was not ready for ninjas.
Who IS ready for ninjas?
No one!  They're ninjas!
I've never even seen a ninja until today.
Except for that dude at the
knife store.
They're probably already gone.
Disappeared into smoke.
Oh, nope.
Well, this settles it.
Black Mesa is a
James Bond villain company.
We have missiles,
robots,
lasers,
sharks,
and ninjas.
Ah!  "Surface Access"!
[grunts]
Dammit...
Eh, maybe I'll level this place.
Whoah!  Holy shit!
It's morning.
How did I not notice this?
Man, I am tripping balls!
Time is moving WAY too fast.
Something's wrong with my brain.
It's like that experiment where they kept
that guy underground in a cave
for a few weeks with no time reference,
and his body adjusted to a 25-hour cycle.
Oh, here we go.
Except, in my case,
my body's waiting to go--
[grunts]
Jesus Christ...
Hey, it opened!
What was I thinking about?
Oh, yeah, I need a watch.
Eh, that's okay. Watches are cheap.
So, what should I do about this suit?
What, with the ninjas
tracking me and all.
I'm starting to like how
it's painted bright orange.
I think it makes people want to shoot me
in the torso instead of the head.
So, should I take it off or leave it on?
I don't know.
The stripper's dilemma.
If I wasn't a fugitive, I could publish
a paper on this and get some money.
I'll wait and keep it on until I find
a car, then ditch it.
HECU #1: Get him!
No!  Cut it out!
[punching]
Urgh...
HECU #1: Heh heh heh.  Nice hit.
HECU #2: Where are we taking
this Freeman guy?
HECU #1: Topside for questioning.
HECU #2: What the hell for?  We got him.
HECU #2: Let's kill him now!
No...
HECU #1: Uh, and if they find the body?
HECU #2: Body?  What body?
HECU #1 and #2: (laughing)
Ah hah hah hah hah hah hah...